Daughters of the American Revolution 084
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Daughters of the American Revolution Yearbooks Collection
1924-1962
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Daughters of the American Revolution. District of Columbia
084
0.5 Linear feet
1 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
The Daughters of the American Revolution was founded in 1890 as a service organization dedicated to the promotion of patriotism, historic preservation, and education. The DAR is open to any woman, at least 18 years of age, who can prove blood lineal descent from an ancestor who aided in achieving American independence. The District of Columbia State Chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution was established in 1891, with local chapters forming as early as 1892. Though there were once as many as 60 local chapters, most have either disbanded or merged together. As of 2020, there are 18 local chapters in D.C.
Custodial History
The materials in this collection were relocated from DC Public Library Special Collection's vertical files and the Cutter collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of Daughters of the American Revolution yearbooks, including the District of Columbia State Chapter and District of Columbia Local Chapters, from 1924-1962.
Yearbooks; Societies and clubs; Women
- Series 1
  - Livingston Manor, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Livingston Manor, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Livingston Manor, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Livingston Manor, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Livingston Manor, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Marcia Burns, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Patriots' Memorial, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Patriots' Memorial, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Patriots' Memorial, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Patriots' Memorial, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Patriots' Memorial, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - State: District of Columbia, 1940-1941, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - State: District of Columbia, 1942-1943, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - State: District of Columbia, 1944-1945, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - State: District of Columbia, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - State: District of Columbia, 1948-1949, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - State: District of Columbia, 1950-1951, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - State: District of Columbia, 1952-1953, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - State: District of Columbia, 1954-1955, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - State: District of Columbia, 1956-1957, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - State: District of Columbia, 1958-1959, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - State: District of Columbia, 1960-1961, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)